<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Scooter&#39;s Important Links on Scott Larson</title>
    <link>http://scottrlarson.com/links/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Scooter&#39;s Important Links on Scott Larson</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>2017 Scott Larson</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 14:48:18 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/links/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Bleeping Computer</title>
      <link>http://scottrlarson.com/links/security/link-bleepingcomputer.com/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2019 13:01:07 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scottrlarson.com/links/security/link-bleepingcomputer.com/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;#1 - &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Bleeping Computer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bleeping Computer® is a information security and technology news publication created in 2004. Millions of visitors come to BleepingComputer.com every month to learn about the latest security threats, technology news, ways to stay protected online, and how to use their computer more efficiently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to news, we provide a wide array of free technical support services, downloads, and self-education tools that allow a user to resolve issues on their computer. Whether you are a novice user here to learn basic concepts about computers or an advanced user infected with ransomware, BleepingComputer can offer custom solutions to your problem for free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of it&amp;rsquo;s focuses is also to allow the novice computer to have a place that they can come and discuss computer/technology problems with their peers and at the same time have a rich resource in which to learn the &amp;ldquo;basics&amp;rdquo; about computers and technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They have found, with extensive experience in helping users that most technical support problems lie not with the computer, but with the fact that the user does not know the &amp;ldquo;basic concepts&amp;rdquo; that underlie all issues of computing. Once a user learns the basic concepts of technology they will be able to express what problems they are having in a more understandable manner, making it easier to be helped by a more experienced user.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The basic concepts of computer technology do not only apply themselves towards fixing problems, but also to every day life. In today&amp;rsquo;s age, computers are here to stay and are only going to be incorporated into our daily life more and more as time goes on. Understanding the basic concepts will allow you to communicate more intelligently about your computer and technology needs and allow you to use your equipment more efficiently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, their goal is to turn your #$@!* computer that never does what you want, to one that you praise as a well tamed tool.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stack Exchange</title>
      <link>http://scottrlarson.com/links/help/link-stackexchange.com/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2019 13:09:35 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scottrlarson.com/links/help/link-stackexchange.com/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;#2 - &lt;a href=&#34;https://stackexchange.com/sites#&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Stack Exchange&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Launched in 2010, the Stack Exchange network comprises 173 Q&amp;amp;A communities including Stack Overflow, the largest, most trusted online community for developers to learn, share their knowledge, and build their careers. Since then, the Stack Exchange network has grown into a top 50 online destination with Stack Overflow alone serving more than 50 million developers every month. Stack Overflow also partners with organizations that seek to leverage technology to innovate. Our products and services are focused on enterprise knowledge sharing, technical recruiting, and advertising.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ifixit</title>
      <link>http://scottrlarson.com/links/repair/link-ifixit.com/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2019 13:22:26 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scottrlarson.com/links/repair/link-ifixit.com/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;#3 - &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ifixit.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;IFixit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;iFixit is a wiki-based site that teaches people how to fix almost anything. Anyone can create a repair manual for a device, and anyone can also edit the existing set of manuals to improve them. The site empowers individuals to share their technical knowledge with the rest of the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I use the ifixit site for disassembly reference for laptops. But I also purchase parts from the site I cannot find anywhere else. I support&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make Use Of</title>
      <link>http://scottrlarson.com/links/news/link-makeuseof.com/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2019 13:34:58 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scottrlarson.com/links/news/link-makeuseof.com/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;#4 - &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.makeuseof.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Make Use Of&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make Use Of is a website that reviews many technologies and offers guides and solutions that make life easier. This is one of my top 5 sites that I recommend to my customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Founded in 2007, MakeUseOf is an online publication that issues tips and guides on how to make the most of the internet, computer software, and mobile apps. Our mission is to help users understand and navigate modern trends in consumer technology.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wilders Security Forums</title>
      <link>http://scottrlarson.com/links/security/link-wilderssecurity.com/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2019 13:38:05 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scottrlarson.com/links/security/link-wilderssecurity.com/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;#5 - &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wilderssecurity.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Wilders Security Forums&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Wilders Security Forums is a Community Based Discussions board about Online Privacy, Security and Data Protection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Wilders Security Organization is a not for profit group that has its public face at Wilders Security Forums. The forum is more than 12 years old with nearly 130,000 members participating in general computing related discussions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Founding date: 2001&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Laptop Buyers Guide</title>
      <link>http://scottrlarson.com/links/guides/link-laptop-buyers-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 09:03:09 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scottrlarson.com/links/guides/link-laptop-buyers-guide/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a really great resource for finding a laptop that meets your specifications. The site reviews laptops and then it has a search tool that allows you to filter laptops based on the recommendation points of each laptop.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.notebookcheck.net/Laptop-Buying-Guide-Tool.13212.0.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://www.notebookcheck.net/Laptop-Buying-Guide-Tool.13212.0.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exfat -vs- Ntfs</title>
      <link>http://scottrlarson.com/links/guides/link-exfat-ntfs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2020 10:49:14 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scottrlarson.com/links/guides/link-exfat-ntfs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A good article on the differences between these two Windows based file systems exfat and ntfs when it comes to portability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lifewire.com/exfat-vs-ntfs-4781790&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://www.lifewire.com/exfat-vs-ntfs-4781790&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Securely Delete Data</title>
      <link>http://scottrlarson.com/links/guides/link-how-to-securely-delete-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2019 11:09:42 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scottrlarson.com/links/guides/link-how-to-securely-delete-data/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ssd.eff.org/en/module/how-delete-your-data-securely-macos&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;How to Delete Your Data Securely on macOS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a good guide that explains how to securely delete data from a Mac, but it also references a PC. These instructions might be beyond the capabilities for the average computer user, but it&amp;rsquo;s still good to know what is involved in securely deleting data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you get rid of an old computer that has data on it, that has not been securely deleted, that data can be mined by people that have an interest in stealing your assets, or impersonating you to hide criminal behavior. Its very difficult, and/or time consuming dealing with identify theft if you do not know how your information is being used without your consent. Think be for you throw away a device that might have information about you that you do not want to fall into the wrong hands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best bet is to hirer me, I can &lt;a href=&#34;http://scottrlarson.com/services/information/security/data/&#34;&gt;securely delete sensitive data&lt;/a&gt; before you recycle or give away your legacy device.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PC Dust Filtering Products</title>
      <link>http://scottrlarson.com/links/desktop/link-pc-dust-filtering-products/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2019 11:27:43 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scottrlarson.com/links/desktop/link-pc-dust-filtering-products/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;The links below are vendors, or products that can help you protect your computer equipment from a dust contained environment. Over time, dust, or micro particles, can cause damage to electronic components. If you live, or work in a environment that contains a lot of dust particles, protecting your electronics from damage prevents down-time and extra costs in replacing components.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;pc-tower-dust-protection&#34;&gt;PC Tower Dust Protection&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dustshield.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://www.dustshield.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;keyboard-covers&#34;&gt;Keyboard Covers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/s?k=keyboard+dust+cover&amp;amp;i=electronics&amp;amp;ref=nb_sb_noss_1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://www.amazon.com/s?k=keyboard+dust+cover&amp;amp;i=electronics&amp;amp;ref=nb_sb_noss_1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Driver Utilities</title>
      <link>http://scottrlarson.com/links/utilities/link-driver-utilities/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 16:30:14 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scottrlarson.com/links/utilities/link-driver-utilities/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sometimes drivers fail to operate correctly and uninstalling them or replacing the files do not always work. When this happens you might need an advanced tools for repair or resolution.
These tools are for professionals that know what they are doing, use with care.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.guru3d.com/files-details/display-driver-uninstaller-download.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;DDU - Driver Display Uninstaller&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Computer Building Basics</title>
      <link>http://scottrlarson.com/links/building/link-computer-building-basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 16:16:37 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scottrlarson.com/links/building/link-computer-building-basics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you were ever wondering how a desktop computer is built, or you need to understand how to build your own, this is a good reference video from newegg.com to get you started. On a side note, and this is not a plug, newegg.com is a great place to purchase hardware. They have good return policies and prices.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lPIXAtNGGCw&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lPIXAtNGGCw&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>File Copy Transfer Utilities</title>
      <link>http://scottrlarson.com/links/utilities/link-file-folder-utilities/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 14:49:14 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scottrlarson.com/links/utilities/link-file-folder-utilities/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When copying a lot of files, sometimes you need an advanced utility. This is a list of tools I use for my services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A good article on the history behind coping files in bulk and a tool that was created to meet that need. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tpcqpc.com/richcopy-microsofts-multi-threaded-file-copy-utility/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;RichCopy – Microsoft’s Multi-Threaded File Copy Utility&lt;/a&gt; is a Windows copy utilities for IT professionals.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fpnet.fr/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Fab&amp;rsquo;s Autobackup&lt;/a&gt; utility is a good tool to migrate Windows account profile data from one computer to another. I copies profile data and helps you setup a new profile with many of the features that need to be working after a successful migration like Outlook Email, and Web Browser History.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
