<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Services on Scott Larson</title>
    <link>http://scottrlarson.com/services/data/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data Services on Scott Larson</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>2017 Scott Larson</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2018 13:03:27 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://scottrlarson.com/services/data/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Erasing/Wiping</title>
      <link>http://scottrlarson.com/services/data/erasing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Dec 2021 10:19:51 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scottrlarson.com/services/data/erasing/</guid>
      <description>If you have an old piece of technology that you want to recycle or reuse, it&amp;rsquo;s important that you have your data erased from the device before you send it off so your data does not fall into the wrong hands. Service Price $25</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cloud Backup Setup Service</title>
      <link>http://scottrlarson.com/services/data/cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2018 13:46:11 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scottrlarson.com/services/data/cloud/</guid>
      <description>I setup cloud backup services, if you need special help in make sure files and folders are backed up.
Service Range Min $50.00  Service Range Max $100.00  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Transfers</title>
      <link>http://scottrlarson.com/services/data/transfers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2018 13:45:10 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scottrlarson.com/services/data/transfers/</guid>
      <description>A data transfer is a service that involves moving, or copying data from one, or more source devices and transferring that data to a target device, or devices, such as another computer or a secondary storage device.
Data/System Transfers/Migrations If you require a data transfer service and you do not know the specifics of your data, like what file types/software you want transferred/migrated or the location of where your data files are stored, a migration audit report is required.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Backup Solutions</title>
      <link>http://scottrlarson.com/services/data/backup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2018 13:44:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scottrlarson.com/services/data/backup/</guid>
      <description>Data Backup and Recovery Solution (Local and Cloud) I can help you setup solution that backs-up important data to a local or cloud based storage device.
Disaster Recovery Backup Solution Storage devices usually have a limited life span due to wear and tear. A disaster recovery solution backs-up your system, programs and personal data. In the event of a hardware loss, or disaster, a recovery of that data can be performed minimizing down-time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Archiving</title>
      <link>http://scottrlarson.com/services/data/archiving/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2018 13:44:27 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scottrlarson.com/services/data/archiving/</guid>
      <description>If you need to have data stored long term, there are methods that will protect your data from wear. I can help you develop a strategy for maintaining a good copy of that data so that you dont lose important information due to wear or device end of life situations.
Request Quote
 Call  On-line    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recovery</title>
      <link>http://scottrlarson.com/services/data/recovery/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2018 13:03:13 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scottrlarson.com/services/data/recovery/</guid>
      <description>Data Recovery Data Recovery is a process of evaluating and attempting to retrieve data that has become inaccessible due to an operating system failure, hardware damage, or due to accidental deletion by the user.
STOP! If you are experiencing performance problems, hangs, freezing, or unrecoverable errors, your storage device might be in the process of failing catastrophically. In addition if you experienced a loss already on a device you are currently using, in both cases, stop using your device and have a diagnostic/analysis performed on the device immediately.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>