<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Troubleshooting on Scott Larson</title>
    <link>http://scottrlarson.com/tags/troubleshooting/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Troubleshooting on Scott Larson</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>2017 Scott Larson</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2019 16:26:43 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://scottrlarson.com/tags/troubleshooting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Laptop</title>
      <link>http://scottrlarson.com/services/computer/repair/laptop/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2019 16:26:43 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scottrlarson.com/services/computer/repair/laptop/</guid>
      <description>When you are having a problem with your laptop&#39;s hardware or software that requires a repair to fix the issue, I offer good prices, expert handling of your issue, with a quick turn around time usually between 24 and 48 hours depending on my availability.
With over twenty years of hardware and software experience, I provide quick and comprehensive repair solutions to the most common and obscure computer problems. Don&#39;t let computer problems frustrate you and effect your productivity, Call me or schedule an appointment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diagnostic</title>
      <link>http://scottrlarson.com/services/computer/repair/diagnostic/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2019 16:26:23 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scottrlarson.com/services/computer/repair/diagnostic/</guid>
      <description>When your device experiences trouble I can provide a professional report on the extent of the problem. Diagnostics are done before any repairs are completed to analyze the scope of the problem and provide a cost/benefit analysis.
 When any repair is authorized on behalf of a diagnostic report, I give you a 25% discount on the diagnostic fee. I deliver cutting edge results to any hardware or software related problem with over twenty years of hardware experience while using the latest hardware diagnostic tools.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Desktop</title>
      <link>http://scottrlarson.com/services/computer/repair/desktop/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2019 16:25:54 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scottrlarson.com/services/computer/repair/desktop/</guid>
      <description>When you are having a problem with your desktops hardware or software that requires a repair to fix the issue, I offer good prices, expert handling of your issue, with a quick turn around time usually between 24 and 48 hours depending on my availability.
With over twenty years of hardware and software experience, I provide quick and comprehensive repair solutions to the most common and obscure computer problems. Don&#39;t let computer problems frustrate you and effect your productivity, Call me or schedule an appointment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upkeep (Hardware)</title>
      <link>http://scottrlarson.com/services/computer/repair/upkeep-hardware/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2019 15:48:51 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scottrlarson.com/services/computer/repair/upkeep-hardware/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Desktops and laptops can suffer from shutdowns, boot failures, errors, and system crashes related to blocked ventilation, aging of parts that protect the hardware from thermal damage, or mis-configured hardware. Having your device properly maintained on a regular basis improves the life of the hardware and can solve system failures that are happening as a result of heat or system mis-configurations by the device manufacturer.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upkeep (General)</title>
      <link>http://scottrlarson.com/services/computer/repair/upkeep-general/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2019 15:48:04 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scottrlarson.com/services/computer/repair/upkeep-general/</guid>
      <description>Having recurring maintenance service in place prevents computer issues from turning into disasters. Regular computer maintenance is more than just an insurance policy. It keeps you informed and in the loop with where you are at any given moment to the status of your technology needs.
 Analyze system for out-of-date hardware and offer cost effective recommendations for replacement&amp;nbsp;(Prevents performance problems with the operation of your computer). Analyze System for Out-of-Date or Non-Functioning Drivers and Software&amp;nbsp;(Prevents problems with the operation of your device).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network</title>
      <link>http://scottrlarson.com/services/information/management/network/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2018 15:11:19 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scottrlarson.com/services/information/management/network/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you have a small home or business network and need setup, maintenance or trouble-shooting with a router, switch or modem I can provide you with a comprehensive analysis/quote on what you need to maintain a healthy network. I also can help you with WiFi setup, and maintenance. If you need good WiFi coverage, are having trouble with interference or speeds I also offer a WiFi Site Survey Service where I can map out your coverage and show you where the weak points are, I also can tell you what kinds of physical problems might be involved in poor signal strength or poor WiFi performance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Website</title>
      <link>http://scottrlarson.com/services/information/management/website/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2018 15:10:58 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scottrlarson.com/services/information/management/website/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I specialize in providing trouble-shooting and back-end maintainance. If you are having an issue with your website, or want to talk with me about a web service that you want for personal, or business use give me a &lt;a href=&#34;http://scottrlarson.com/#contact&#34;&gt;call&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;http://scottrlarson.com/#contact&#34;&gt;email&lt;/a&gt; me about your project, or issue.  See my previous projects involving web site migrations, and &lt;a href=&#34;http://scottrlarson.com/projects/network/tantra.com/&#34;&gt;web site troubleshooting&lt;/a&gt; if you are interested in some of my history involving my technical expertise.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Consultation</title>
      <link>http://scottrlarson.com/services/computer/assistance/consultation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 12:53:52 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scottrlarson.com/services/computer/assistance/consultation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I offer one on one in-shop, and at-location consultations. I sit down with you, record information about your problem, and offer a analysis/resolution on the spot, or for a larger project I can provide you with a cost estimate. This information can be handed to you in print format, or emailed to you electronically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I give advise, and offer solutions to any computer related technical challenge. Check my &lt;a href=&#34;http://scottrlarson.com/#rates&#34;&gt;Availability Hours &amp;amp; Rates&lt;/a&gt; for more information about costs and my availability.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tantra.com: Diagnose &amp; Repair: HTML Website Loading Stuck Issue</title>
      <link>http://scottrlarson.com/projects/network/tantra.com/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Mar 2001 13:49:14 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scottrlarson.com/projects/network/tantra.com/</guid>
      <description>Legacy HTML image caching code caused site to stop loading on certain modern web browsers - tracked down from client side using web load tools and reported problem to developer&amp;rsquo;s allowing them to remove legacy code that was causing the issue.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>