<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Shelter-in-place on Scott Larson</title>
    <link>http://scottrlarson.com/tags/shelter-in-place/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Shelter-in-place on Scott Larson</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>2017 Scott Larson</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 11:00:52 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://scottrlarson.com/tags/shelter-in-place/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Why everyone should use a password manager</title>
      <link>http://scottrlarson.com/publications/publication-why-password-managers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 11:00:52 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scottrlarson.com/publications/publication-why-password-managers/</guid>
      <description>We are in an age where password security is becoming very important to our ability to function in society, but not for the reasons you expect. The password strength, although a problem, isn&amp;rsquo;t the real problem. The real problem is having to remember passwords for the multitude of online accounts we are forced to create to survive in the modern age of technology. In a survey performed last year by Digital Guardian, an average person or business associates their email address with 130 accounts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Part 1 Scam Avoidance: How to Spot and Protect Yourself from Scams</title>
      <link>http://scottrlarson.com/publications/publication-scam-avoidance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 11:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scottrlarson.com/publications/publication-scam-avoidance/</guid>
      <description>This is the 1st part of a 3 part series in protecting yourself from on-line and of-line scams.
With the 2020 COVID-19 crisis causing many to work from home, it&amp;rsquo;s more important than ever to have a set of tools to deal with threats that come your way.
In this publication, I will help you identify threats so that you can avoid being deceived by malicious calls to action. If your device has been compromised by a scam, its important to learn how to deal with an attack after the fact.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Part 2 Scam Avoidance: Avoiding Scams</title>
      <link>http://scottrlarson.com/publications/publication-scam-avoidance2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 11:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scottrlarson.com/publications/publication-scam-avoidance2/</guid>
      <description>This is the 2nd part of a 3 part series in protecting yourself from on-line and of-line scams. In part 1 I attempted to make you aware of some of the common ways in which a scammer operates. In this part of series, I will talk about ways you can avoid scams by being aware what to look for, and using technology to help you avoid scamms altogeather.
 The best security is awareness The psychology behind decision making Avoiding Scams Protecting yourself after the Scam Protect your on-line accounts Conclusion Updates: Spying on the Scammers Video Terms  Avoiding Scams Search Results Skipping Ads with an Adblocker</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Part 3 Scam Avoidance: Protecting yourself after the Scam</title>
      <link>http://scottrlarson.com/publications/publication-scam-avoidance3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 11:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scottrlarson.com/publications/publication-scam-avoidance3/</guid>
      <description>This is 3rd part of a 3 part series in protecting yourself from on-line and of-line scams. In part 2 I discussed some ways you can avoid scams before you become a victum. In this part of the series I will outline some ways to handle yourself after the fact.
 The best security is awareness The psychology behind decision making Avoiding Scams Protecting yourself after the Scam Protect your on-line accounts Conclusion Updates: Spying on the Scammers Video Terms  Protecting yourself after the Scam If you have already been a victim of an scam.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Restoring your digital life from backup after a disaster</title>
      <link>http://scottrlarson.com/publications/publication-restoring-life-backup-disaster/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2019 14:44:47 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scottrlarson.com/publications/publication-restoring-life-backup-disaster/</guid>
      <description>Learn why solely backing up your data isn&amp;rsquo;t always enough to recover from a disaster.
In this publication, you will learn about:
 What is disaster recovery backup, and why should I care? How a little planning can drive a successful disaster recovery Why waiting for a disaster to happen before you plan is a bad idea Understanding technology terms  Knowing the difference between backup and disaster recovery, understanding key technology terms, and evaluating software along with storage options can help you develop an effective plan for avoiding the consequences of data loss and downtime after a catastrophe strikes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Identity Theft Protection, and do you need it?</title>
      <link>http://scottrlarson.com/publications/publication-id-theft-what-why/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2019 12:33:54 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scottrlarson.com/publications/publication-id-theft-what-why/</guid>
      <description>It is relatively easy from the standpoint of a thief to impersonate your online identity and assume your financial standing. Using your identity, a thief can open up a line of credit under your name and go on a shopping spree making you assume all of the responsibility until you rectify the problem. As more and more of our personal information gets warehoused online, protecting information against theft is a continuing challenge on both sides of the fence, customers and financial institutions alike.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Protecting Your Smartphone From Being Hacked</title>
      <link>http://scottrlarson.com/publications/publication-smartphone-protection/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2019 11:21:57 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scottrlarson.com/publications/publication-smartphone-protection/</guid>
      <description>Smartphones are much more than simple tools to make calls and take pictures. They have become our personal assistants. Storing everything about us. On the one hand, using a smartphone for our day to day living makes life much more convenient. On the other hand, storing all that info about our life on one device that we take with us on the go, opens us up to data theft. It&amp;rsquo;s nothing to be afraid of, its important for our society to be open.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>