<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Contemplations on Scott Larson</title>
    <link>http://scottrlarson.com/tags/contemplations/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Contemplations on Scott Larson</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>2017 Scott Larson</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 May 2022 13:51:26 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/contemplations/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Mental Health Awareness Month</title>
      <link>http://scottrlarson.com/reflections/reflection-mental-health-awareness-month/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2022 13:51:26 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scottrlarson.com/reflections/reflection-mental-health-awareness-month/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I heard about Mental Health Awareness Month from another Youtuber &amp;ldquo;Ben Gravey&amp;rdquo; a surfer who was an alcoholic who changed his life through surfing. I had a life-changing experience myself and I thought it would be a good idea to share it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2017 I had a brain hemorrhage. The doctor said it was brought on by out-of-control blood pressure. To be fair, my blood was high pressure back then so they may have been right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent a couple of weeks in the hospital relearning how to use my brain to walk. It was like drawing a picture of the hospital in my mind so I could navigate.
During this time, I realized how deeply sad I was about my life, and how I felt like I wasn&amp;rsquo;t really living. I attempt to write a book about that, well I wrote a badly edited book on my understanding of life and its purpose a year after that incident. The book is called &amp;ldquo;Most Improved&amp;rdquo; and you can find it on Amazon.
Later on, a joined an organization called the Mankind Project. The mission of MKP is to help men become better men, one man at a time. If you do a search on google for the project, the first results you likely will get are about MKP being a cult.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found that the organization, as far as organizations go, is far from what I understand that a cult is. MKP uses various disciplines to help men tap into their own potential. What&amp;rsquo;s important about MKP is that, even though there are agreements everyone in the organization agrees to, such as not trying to fix other men, and using I statements. My understanding is that MKP&amp;rsquo;s organizational structure has its roots in an autonomous, egalitarian perspective. There are men in the organization who project their issues of control onto the organization, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to go too far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MKP helped me center the focus of my mental health work on my internal problems, rather than the outside world. In my judgment, most organizations try to focus on the external problems of the world to fix everything. I am a firm believer that all the world&amp;rsquo;s problems have a foundation within each individual, and only when, every human on the planet or at least enough humans on the planet make this shift, very little will change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I say within, I mean those feelings or reactions that well up inside an individual, that take over without warning. In the Mankind Project, we call them shadows because they operate behind the scenes. By shining light on these issues, deliberately, we get closer to the real issues that drive all the problems in the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Putting aside chemical/psychical problems with the brain, all mental health issues boil down to issues of avoidance or denial of life&amp;rsquo;s challenges. Maybe as a kid growing up, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t able to understand this, and maybe I didn&amp;rsquo;t have a choice back then, but now I do. I have a choice and responsibility to myself and others to work out these issues, with the help of others, because one of the things about being an authentic human, is knowing when I needed help and asking for help, and acting on the courage that I know was within me to ask for that help.
Mental Health, for me, is about finding the courage to act on small aspects of my healing and widening the view of what&amp;rsquo;s possible, bit by bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A book that helped me with this was &amp;ldquo;Constructive Living&amp;rdquo; by David K. Reynolds.
Constructive Living taught me that wasting away thinking about why my life isn&amp;rsquo;t the way I wanted it to be was a recipe for disaster. I had to bring my problems into some action. For me, it was about tending to all the things I often let go of, regardless of how I felt. Over time, that helped me to build empowering patterns of behavior which got me out of my depression. I still sink into states of sorrow, but I have men that I can rely on now to help me through my problems. Being alone with my thoughts was the worst problem to overcome for me because I am so used to being in my own world. Being determined to make real changes in my life, I had enough with doing things the way I always did them and tried something new.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is how I continue to heal myself. I pray that you find your own way. It&amp;rsquo;s never too late for anything.
Scott Larson.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Return to Laurentum</title>
      <link>http://scottrlarson.com/reflections/reflection-return-laurentum/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2020 07:59:21 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scottrlarson.com/reflections/reflection-return-laurentum/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dear kinsman, I am writing this letter to you in the message of the spirit in the hopes that you will receive it one day. You have been missing for a generation. We have heard from the Great Soul that you have become lost in the &amp;ldquo;Forgotten Land&amp;rdquo; where many of our brethren have gone missing. We wonder why you have taken a detour from your pilgrimage to the final resting place. Your stop in that place worries me. The Forgotten lives behind a false image of what can never truly be. This illusion, that they all play a part in, puts a strain on us all. The strain comes from a knowledge that life before was vastly different than the life they live today. We are concerned that your life force has been caught between worlds while you remain in that place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Forgotten are tricked into serving ideologies that cause divisions all across the Earth. Existence has become stale by this soliptic[^1] existence. There&amp;rsquo;s is this sadness we feel for you, by remaining, your psychological and spiritual body suffers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How can one maintain a fluid and dynamic life, when all the focus is on maintaining the group, at the expense of the individual? They are slowly all suffering a loss of identity. This loss shows up in the building up of rage in that younger generation. Every generation, there are those that have forgotten who they were, and end their very own lives. They suffer through substance abuse and hopelessness. It is painful for us to see the innocent fall because of this sickness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kinsman, rise up! Return home! You belong with your people who you left long ago out of a curiosity for a life that is not real. You have been caught by a mere memory that only interests, but does not replenish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Return to Laurentum[^2] where the waters replenish and the tree of life restores. We miss your contribution to the tribe, and many of us are gravely concerned that already, too many have been lost to this &amp;ldquo;Forgotten Land&amp;rdquo;. If your memory has been lost, visit the pool of insight and I will leave a token there for you to find your way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Goodbye my kinsmen, I look forward to the day of your return.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[1]: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.etymonline.com/word/*sol-#etymonline_v_53253&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;*sol- &lt;/a&gt;also solə-, Proto-Indo-European root meaning &amp;ldquo;whole, well-kept.&amp;rdquo; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.etymonline.com/word/elliptic#etymonline_v_32296&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;elliptic (adj.)&lt;/a&gt;&amp;ldquo;pertaining to an ellipse; having the form of an ellipse,&amp;rdquo; 1726, from Greek elleiptikos &amp;ldquo;pertaining to an ellipse,&amp;rdquo; from elleipein &amp;ldquo;to fall short, leave out&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[2]: According to Virgil&amp;rsquo;s The Aeneid the city Laurentum and its people the Laurentines gained its name because the Laurel tree was Latinus&amp;rsquo; favourite.[&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Laurentum#cite_note-8&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;8]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Laurentum#cite_note-8)&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Laurentum#cite_note-8)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Life is a treacherous climb</title>
      <link>http://scottrlarson.com/reflections/contemplation-treacherous-climb/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2020 12:47:26 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scottrlarson.com/reflections/contemplation-treacherous-climb/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The sun is a friend to me. It lights up the way to myself, filling me with gratitude and wellbeing. Even when it shines in my face while I&amp;rsquo;m trying to write. I cannot become too annoyed. I know that to become annoyed is to invite a breakdown. Being a man requires calmness and patience. For myself, my world, and my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every day I get up when the sun rises, and go to sleep when the sun sets. I didn&amp;rsquo;t decide to do this, it just happened. There is a healing power in the activity of revolving my life around the sun. Being awake at the crack of dawn gives me a certain earthly perspective on life. When I was revolving my life around the night, my life revolved around the dark sun of unearthly tendencies. I had this need to indirectly harm myself, and others through thoughts and speech.  It wasn&amp;rsquo;t until my awakening that I realized that I disconnected myself from the life of the planet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am a learning man. I have made many mistakes in my youth. Mostly centered around lack of self-reliance. Not necessarily the self-reliance that I learned as a young adult, which is primarily about making a living and  obtaining independence. No, It&amp;rsquo;s a self-reliance that develops out of refusing to let circumstances control my thinking. In the past, when I lost my freedom,  I wallowed in sorrow and anger. Anger that I was wronged, sadness for freedom I gave up fighting against the law. By my own hand, I created the conditions of my life. Not only did I go against the divine law of life, I let my own pain of being in a world I created, upset my natural equilibrium that I came to this earth with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I spend my days undoing that harm. This is good.  It is right that I suffered. Suffering taught me how to really live.  Life is treacherous climb, each handhold is a series of movements into an alignment, or misalignment with what is. If I slip on a handhold of fear, or on a handhold of self-righteousness, I&amp;rsquo;ll fall into the abyss. No, I will grab the handhold&amp;rsquo;s of love and calmness so I can ascend onto a solid ground of peace.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Armstrong Woods Reflections</title>
      <link>http://scottrlarson.com/reflections/travelogue-armstrong-woods-reflections/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2019 09:52:19 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scottrlarson.com/reflections/travelogue-armstrong-woods-reflections/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I come alive when I get out of my own way. After I had a Cerebral Hemorrhage back in 2017, my physiology changed. I will call this health challenge &amp;ldquo;The Event&amp;rdquo; moving forward. A turning point in my life that was on the level of how an earthquake shakes up the landscape. I spontaneously developed different habits and goals for my life. And it changed the kind of person I was destined to be.  New habits sprung up automatically and without any prompting:  a daily morning regiment, increased productivity in my pursuits, an unending peace, and a lack of fear for the future that I cannot explain. I enjoy habits that bring on new pursuits, but I still carry this overwhelming feeling of loss with me everywhere I go. I believe &amp;ldquo;The Event&amp;rdquo; created a sole soul purpose within me, to become a new man. One that is patient, kind and understanding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have noticed throughout my life that certain mental states have this quality of frustration, pushing me to my limits. Or at least I allow this mental force, to push me into places that I&amp;rsquo;d rather not go. My first thought was to get out into the woods. How I missed walking in the woods and listening to that deep sound of silence.  So one weekend instead of doing my normal routine, I packed up my gear and headed out to Armstrong Woods, in Guerneville, CA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My journey started on the East Ridge path.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://scottrlarson.com/img/travelogues/armstrong-woods-reflections/map.png&#34; alt=&#34;Map of Armstrong Woods&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How utterly quiet this forest is. The only sound is the wind, and an occasional squawk from a bird. I look back at the parking lot, wondering when I am going to return. Will I get lost this time? I think not. I get to the first turn, stopping in the middle of the path, hoping to see some sign of a Raven (a sign I associate with interpersonal change). As I look for photo opportunities, two men in their sixties walk past me. One says to me, &amp;ldquo;A man after my own heart, one who takes his time.&amp;rdquo; I laugh as they pass, there is irony in that statement. Most of my life, I was rushing from one experience to the next, paying little regard for the importance of the moment. I&amp;rsquo;m learning, that life is really about giving more than taking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the two men pass, I look around again. I see two Redwoods growing out of the same place on the earth. They reach into the sky, drawing strength from each other. Redwoods often grow as close together as possible to protect each other from the elements. I almost lost my balance on the steep incline, trying to pano-capture the pair with my SmartPhone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://scottrlarson.com/img/travelogues/armstrong-woods-reflections/two-redwoods.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;The two redwoods growing up together&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I turn back to the path to leave, and see a feather on the ground next to a neighboring Redwood. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if it is an eagle feather. Eagle&amp;rsquo;s are one of the strongest birds in existence. For me, eagle feathers are a symbol of what&amp;rsquo;s most important in life. I decide that this is a symbol that the universe is much stronger, and bigger than any problem I might have. A humbling feeling sets in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://scottrlarson.com/img/travelogues/armstrong-woods-reflections/feather.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Light as a feather, but strong as a tree trunk&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Farther along the path, I came upon a bench that had fallen over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://scottrlarson.com/img/travelogues/armstrong-woods-reflections/bench.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;The broken on the mend&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This bench will be mended one day, to be a place of peace and rest for weary travelers. It reminds me of my once broken life. Now I stand erect, and unbroken until the ending of the world, carrying myself though these trial-by-fire days. The world is in such a state of change it’s almost unbearable to me. There is so much conflict, but also so much peace in the world to be discovered. The one that gets realized is the one that is fed the most, I gather.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I see a little house in the distance, across the stream.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://scottrlarson.com/img/travelogues/armstrong-woods-reflections/cabin.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;The house above the stream&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s probably a storage shed for the park, but in my mind&amp;rsquo;s eye, I see a small cabin built on a hill in the forest. A man of the woods arrives. Opens the door, and in the window I see him lay down to rest after a long day. Life in the forest doesn&amp;rsquo;t require much. Just food, shelter, and a warm hearth. The cabin is right on the edge of a chasm. At the bottom, the sound of a stream can be heard. This day-dream reminds me of a movie, about a veteran that lived in a forest preserve with his daughter. They were caught by some authority figures. I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure that the daughter wanted to be caught, she looked tired of living in the wild. They eventually found themselves in a camp where she was able to stay with others. Her father appeared to be uneasy in their new company and wanted to leave, but she stayed. He went back into the wild deal with his demons, and the daughter stayed behind. The community left food out for their lost loved ones. Life is best when we are free to deal with our personal demons, on our own terms, without the forced interference of a sick society. A society that uses violence to wall off what we do not understand, so we don&amp;rsquo;t have to remember how lost we have become.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found a stone sitting area, it reminded me of a relic from a bygone age. This one is missing a fountain in its center. In my imagination, celebrations happen here.  A marriage is happening, or a stage play. People are laughing, and enjoying each other&amp;rsquo;s company. This structure is in the center of a village, where the villagers meet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://scottrlarson.com/img/travelogues/armstrong-woods-reflections/stone-sitting-place.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Fountain Center&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I imagine this Redwood to have a cave at the base of the trunk. I go in, and never come out. But once I&amp;rsquo;m down there, I go through my own personal trial-by-fire. Whatever is holding me back in my life remains, up on the surface, I find the solution to it here. Underneath the earth, where it&amp;rsquo;s dark, I come to an understanding with myself. I will take heart, and not take life for granted, as I once did when I was young.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://scottrlarson.com/img/travelogues/armstrong-woods-reflections/door.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Door to the redwoods&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This looks like an outcropping of rock formations, but it&amp;rsquo;s the roots of an enormous Redwood tree. It&amp;rsquo;s called &amp;ldquo;Armstrong Tree&amp;rdquo; by the park. One day it had enough, and fell over. But it&amp;rsquo;s still here, after all this time. Just like us. We can fall over, but we get back up, and we can be remembered for what we do after we fall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://scottrlarson.com/img/travelogues/armstrong-woods-reflections/roots-armstrong-tree.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Armstrong Tree&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Long ago I did a small study of my last name. The origin of the name &amp;ldquo;Larson&amp;rdquo; comes from the historic Scandinavian country of Sweden. The surname &amp;ldquo;Larson&amp;rdquo; is derived from the Nordic word Lars, which is a pet form of the name Lawrence. This name is, in turn, derived from the Latin name Laurentius, which means: &amp;ldquo;Man from Laurentium&amp;rdquo;. Laurentium is a town in Italy named for its laurel trees. The bay leaf from a laurel tree has healing properties and Native Americans used it to heal many maladies. I find the connection between the name and the tree very interesting, as the smell of the leaf always brings me peace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://scottrlarson.com/img/travelogues/armstrong-woods-reflections/leaves-bay.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Picture of a bay leaf&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A real-life starts with being patient like these trees, kind like the wind, and understanding like the elderly men I met on the path. I grieve for something lost on the path of my life, but the discovery of what is true and vital to my wellbeing brings me closer to that piece of myself that was lost long ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;author-s-note&#34;&gt;Author&amp;rsquo;s Note&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This piece would not have been possible without the help of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://mkp.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Mankind Project&lt;/a&gt;.  After &amp;ldquo;The Event&amp;rdquo;, I was led to Mankind Project&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://mankindproject.org/new-warrior-training-adventure/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;New Warrior Training Adventure&lt;/a&gt; where I discovered my calling.  The Mankind Project is an organization that helps men become ethical creators of life in this modern age of decadence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can discover more about what  MKP&amp;rsquo;s New Warrior Training Adventure is like by reading &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.scottrlarson.com/testimonials/testimonial-mkp/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;my testimonial&lt;/a&gt; about the effect this event had on my life. If you want to know what happened to me before all of this, check out my book &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.scottrlarson.com/publications/publication-most-improved/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Most Improved&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; and  &lt;a href=&#34;http://scottrlarson.com/#contact&#34;&gt;Contact&lt;/a&gt; me if you have questions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
