<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ethics on Scott Larson</title>
    <link>http://scottrlarson.com/tags/ethics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ethics on Scott Larson</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>2017 Scott Larson</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2020 07:59:21 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://scottrlarson.com/tags/ethics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Return to Laurentum</title>
      <link>http://scottrlarson.com/reflections/reflection-return-laurentum/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2020 07:59:21 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scottrlarson.com/reflections/reflection-return-laurentum/</guid>
      <description>Dear kinsman, I am writing this letter to you in the message of the spirit in the hopes that you will receive it one day. You have been missing for a generation. We have heard from the Great Soul that you have become lost in the &amp;ldquo;Forgotten Land&amp;rdquo; where many of our brethren have gone missing. We wonder why you have taken a detour from your pilgrimage to the final resting place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Life is a treacherous climb</title>
      <link>http://scottrlarson.com/reflections/contemplation-treacherous-climb/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2020 12:47:26 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scottrlarson.com/reflections/contemplation-treacherous-climb/</guid>
      <description>The sun is a friend to me. It lights up the way to myself, filling me with gratitude and wellbeing. Even when it shines in my face while I&amp;rsquo;m trying to write. I cannot become too annoyed. I know that to become annoyed is to invite a breakdown. Being a man requires calmness and patience. For myself, my world, and my life.
Every day I get up when the sun rises, and go to sleep when the sun sets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Armstrong Woods Reflections</title>
      <link>http://scottrlarson.com/reflections/travelogue-armstrong-woods-reflections/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2019 09:52:19 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scottrlarson.com/reflections/travelogue-armstrong-woods-reflections/</guid>
      <description>I come alive when I get out of my own way. After I had a Cerebral Hemorrhage back in 2017, my physiology changed. I will call this health challenge &amp;ldquo;The Event&amp;rdquo; moving forward. A turning point in my life that was on the level of how an earthquake shakes up the landscape. I spontaneously developed different habits and goals for my life. And it changed the kind of person I was destined to be.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>