<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Media Streaming on Scott Larson</title>
    <link>http://scottrlarson.com/tags/media-streaming/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Media Streaming on Scott Larson</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>2017 Scott Larson</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2019 05:30:31 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://scottrlarson.com/tags/media-streaming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Ebook Publishing Process</title>
      <link>http://scottrlarson.com/updates/update-process-publishing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2019 05:30:31 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scottrlarson.com/updates/update-process-publishing/</guid>
      <description>I am a author, publisher, and ebook conversion specialist. I got my start developing websites about 5 years after the internet was in fruition. During the beginning of 2019, my first book &amp;ldquo;Most Improved&amp;rdquo; was authored, and published in digital form. I then converted the digital format to a print version so my audience can experience both formats. I can do the same for you.
If you are looking to convert your manuscript to a ebook, or you are just thinking about finding another way to format your documents so you can easily get them to you customers in a way they can read them, on any device, with out a major hassle, then this document is for you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smooth Video Playback</title>
      <link>http://scottrlarson.com/updates/update-smooth-video-playback/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2019 11:24:31 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scottrlarson.com/updates/update-smooth-video-playback/</guid>
      <description>Playing video online or off smoothly has some minimum hardware requirements if you want to avoid hassles:
 Processor: 2.4 Ghz Dual Core Processor. Graphics Card: 256 MB VRAM, 600Mhz Core Clock RAM: 4 GB  If you do not know what specifications your device has, there are a few ways to check, on a PC the easiest way is to open a Run Dialog Box. Hold the Windows key down and press &amp;lsquo;R&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>