<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Repair on Scott Larson</title>
    <link>http://scottrlarson.com/services/computer/repair/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Repair on Scott Larson</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>2017 Scott Larson</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 15:58:48 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://scottrlarson.com/services/computer/repair/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>System Configuration Setup &amp; Upgrades</title>
      <link>http://scottrlarson.com/services/computer/repair/system-configuration-upgrade/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Dec 2021 10:15:43 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scottrlarson.com/services/computer/repair/system-configuration-upgrade/</guid>
      <description>New desktops and laptops often are delivered with out-of-date windows components and hardware specific drivers and firmware. By upgrading and updating these components, something that is not easily done by just letting the Windows Update Service do all the heavy lifting, downtime and frustration is minimized working with a computer system that is not fully ready for operation out of the box. Also new devices are shipped with all of the Windows features enabled and in many cases, can get in the way of a smooth functioning system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Custom Computer Modifications</title>
      <link>http://scottrlarson.com/services/computer/repair/custom-computer-modifications/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 09:20:05 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scottrlarson.com/services/computer/repair/custom-computer-modifications/</guid>
      <description>I perform all types of modifications to improve performance and stability. I also modify hardware configurations to fix a broken parts. I repair mounts, and add thermal solutions that extend the capabilities of many stock computer desktops and laptops.
Modifications are only needed when some aspect of the model doesn&amp;rsquo;t perform to specification and then a custom solution needs to be implemented. I have over 20 years of experience in performing these types of repairs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Laptop</title>
      <link>http://scottrlarson.com/services/computer/repair/laptop/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2019 16:26:43 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scottrlarson.com/services/computer/repair/laptop/</guid>
      <description>When you are having a problem with your laptop&#39;s hardware or software that requires a repair to fix the issue, I offer good prices, expert handling of your issue, with a quick turn around time usually between 24 and 48 hours depending on my availability.
With over twenty years of hardware and software experience, I provide quick and comprehensive repair solutions to the most common and obscure computer problems. Don&#39;t let computer problems frustrate you and effect your productivity, Call me or schedule an appointment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diagnostic</title>
      <link>http://scottrlarson.com/services/computer/repair/diagnostic/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2019 16:26:23 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scottrlarson.com/services/computer/repair/diagnostic/</guid>
      <description>When your device experiences trouble I can provide a professional report on the extent of the problem. Diagnostics are done before any repairs are completed to analyze the scope of the problem and provide a cost/benefit analysis.
 When any repair is authorized on behalf of a diagnostic report, I give you a 25% discount on the diagnostic fee. I deliver cutting edge results to any hardware or software related problem with over twenty years of hardware experience while using the latest hardware diagnostic tools.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Desktop</title>
      <link>http://scottrlarson.com/services/computer/repair/desktop/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2019 16:25:54 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scottrlarson.com/services/computer/repair/desktop/</guid>
      <description>When you are having a problem with your desktops hardware or software that requires a repair to fix the issue, I offer good prices, expert handling of your issue, with a quick turn around time usually between 24 and 48 hours depending on my availability.
With over twenty years of hardware and software experience, I provide quick and comprehensive repair solutions to the most common and obscure computer problems. Don&#39;t let computer problems frustrate you and effect your productivity, Call me or schedule an appointment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upkeep (Hardware)</title>
      <link>http://scottrlarson.com/services/computer/repair/upkeep-hardware/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2019 15:48:51 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scottrlarson.com/services/computer/repair/upkeep-hardware/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Desktops and laptops can suffer from shutdowns, boot failures, errors, and system crashes related to blocked ventilation, aging of parts that protect the hardware from thermal damage, or mis-configured hardware. Having your device properly maintained on a regular basis improves the life of the hardware and can solve system failures that are happening as a result of heat or system mis-configurations by the device manufacturer.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upkeep (General)</title>
      <link>http://scottrlarson.com/services/computer/repair/upkeep-general/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2019 15:48:04 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scottrlarson.com/services/computer/repair/upkeep-general/</guid>
      <description>Having recurring maintenance service in place prevents computer issues from turning into disasters. Regular computer maintenance is more than just an insurance policy. It keeps you informed and in the loop with where you are at any given moment to the status of your technology needs.
 Analyze system for out-of-date hardware and offer cost effective recommendations for replacement&amp;nbsp;(Prevents performance problems with the operation of your computer). Analyze System for Out-of-Date or Non-Functioning Drivers and Software&amp;nbsp;(Prevents problems with the operation of your device).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Malware Cleanup</title>
      <link>http://scottrlarson.com/services/computer/repair/cleanup/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2019 10:57:35 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scottrlarson.com/services/computer/repair/cleanup/</guid>
      <description>If your device became infected by malware, I offer clean-up services that can resolve most infection related issues involving drive by attacks, trojans, adware, virus, rootkits, fake security solutions and more.
Service Price $164  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Online</title>
      <link>http://scottrlarson.com/services/computer/repair/online/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 16:18:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scottrlarson.com/services/computer/repair/online/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you have a question or problem with your device, and your Internet connection is still working, I can service your device over the Internet. I can speak with you over the phone while I am looking at the problem and give you a cost analysis.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>