<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Repair on Scott Larson</title>
    <link>http://scottrlarson.com/services/computer/repair/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Repair on Scott Larson</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>2017 Scott Larson</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 15:58:48 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/services/computer/repair/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>System Configuration Setup &amp; Upgrades</title>
      <link>http://scottrlarson.com/services/computer/repair/system-configuration-upgrade/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Dec 2021 10:15:43 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scottrlarson.com/services/computer/repair/system-configuration-upgrade/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;New desktops and laptops often are delivered with out-of-date windows components and hardware specific drivers and firmware. By upgrading and updating these components, something that is not easily done by just letting the Windows Update Service do all the heavy lifting, downtime and frustration is minimized working with a computer system that is not fully ready for operation out of the box. Also new devices are shipped with all of the Windows features enabled and in many cases, can get in the way of a smooth functioning system. Many of these features are often not used by the owner and just take up space on your disk and cause performance bottlenecks. I work on the desktop environment by removing unwanted software, I.E Manufacturer loaded software that deliver adverts designed to compel you purchase 3rd party products, and reconfigure Windows to operate with a minimal set of features that can be enabled at a later date, on a as-needed basis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your device is running slow, or you are having reoccurring problems with device stability, have it checked out. I use the latest tools and technology to get your device&amp;rsquo;s performance up to a standard you can live with. I will check startup programs, services, drivers, the amount of free memory, provide resource tuning, and check your storage configuration for performance and stability gains. This can be a much more affordable solution  than purchasing a new computer, depending on its end-of-life date. I will also recommend hardware upgrades that are needed to keep your computer performing in top shape.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;quote-panel-container&#34;&gt;
	&lt;div class=&#34;quote-panel-label&#34;&gt;
  	&lt;p&gt;Request Quote&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;quote-panel-item&#34;&gt;
  	&lt;div class=&#34;quote-panel-button&#34;&gt;
  		&lt;a href=&#34;http://scottrlarson.com/services/computer/assistance/phone&#34;&gt;Call&lt;/a&gt;
  	&lt;/div&gt;
  	&lt;div class=&#34;quote-panel-button&#34;&gt;
  		&lt;a href=&#34;http://scottrlarson.com/services/computer/assistance/quote&#34;&gt;On-line&lt;/a&gt;
  	&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Custom Computer Modifications</title>
      <link>http://scottrlarson.com/services/computer/repair/custom-computer-modifications/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 09:20:05 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scottrlarson.com/services/computer/repair/custom-computer-modifications/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://scottrlarson.com/img/highlights/thermal-solution-modification-montage.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Custom m.2 Laptop Thermal Solution&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I perform all types of modifications to improve performance and stability. I also modify hardware configurations to fix a broken parts. I repair mounts, and add thermal solutions that extend the capabilities of many stock computer desktops and laptops.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Modifications are only needed when some aspect of the model doesn&amp;rsquo;t perform to specification and then a custom solution needs to be implemented. I have over 20 years of experience in performing these types of repairs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;quote-panel-container&#34;&gt;
	&lt;div class=&#34;quote-panel-label&#34;&gt;
  	&lt;p&gt;Request Quote&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;quote-panel-item&#34;&gt;
  	&lt;div class=&#34;quote-panel-button&#34;&gt;
  		&lt;a href=&#34;http://scottrlarson.com/services/computer/assistance/phone&#34;&gt;Call&lt;/a&gt;
  	&lt;/div&gt;
  	&lt;div class=&#34;quote-panel-button&#34;&gt;
  		&lt;a href=&#34;http://scottrlarson.com/services/computer/assistance/quote&#34;&gt;On-line&lt;/a&gt;
  	&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Laptop</title>
      <link>http://scottrlarson.com/services/computer/repair/laptop/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2019 16:26:43 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scottrlarson.com/services/computer/repair/laptop/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When you are having a problem with your laptop&#39;s hardware or software that requires a repair to fix the issue, I offer good prices, expert handling of your issue, with a quick turn around time usually between 24 and 48 hours depending on my availability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With over twenty years of hardware and software experience, I provide quick and comprehensive repair solutions to the most common and obscure computer problems. Don&#39;t let computer problems frustrate you and effect your productivity, &lt;a href=&#34;http://scottrlarson.com/services/computer/assistance/phone/&#34;&gt;Call&lt;/a&gt; me or &lt;a href=&#34;http://scottrlarson.com/#contact&#34;&gt;schedule an appointment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;product-body&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you are not sure what the problem is with your device please request a &lt;a href=&#34;diagnostic&#34;&gt;diagnostic&lt;/a&gt;. My diagnostic service allows for proper testing to occur so that complications prior to a repair are minimized.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you are requesting this repair service as part of a previous Diagnostic service, you will receive half-off of the diagnostic service fee as a credit upon completion of repairs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This Fee is per device. If you need more than one device repaired please order more than one Repair Service.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This fee does not include the costs of replacement parts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I guaranty my work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Replacement parts are guaranteed to be free from defects for up to one year minus the shipping cost for the return item and the replacement part.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;quote-panel-container&#34;&gt;
	&lt;div class=&#34;quote-panel-label&#34;&gt;
  	&lt;p&gt;Request Quote&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;quote-panel-item&#34;&gt;
  	&lt;div class=&#34;quote-panel-button&#34;&gt;
  		&lt;a href=&#34;http://scottrlarson.com/services/computer/assistance/phone&#34;&gt;Call&lt;/a&gt;
  	&lt;/div&gt;
  	&lt;div class=&#34;quote-panel-button&#34;&gt;
  		&lt;a href=&#34;http://scottrlarson.com/services/computer/assistance/quote&#34;&gt;On-line&lt;/a&gt;
  	&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diagnostic</title>
      <link>http://scottrlarson.com/services/computer/repair/diagnostic/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2019 16:26:23 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scottrlarson.com/services/computer/repair/diagnostic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When your device experiences trouble I can provide a professional report on the extent of the problem. Diagnostics are done before any &lt;a href=&#34;../repair&#34;&gt;repairs&lt;/a&gt; are completed to analyze the scope of the problem and provide a cost/benefit analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li class=&#34;service-list-items&#34;&gt;When any repair is authorized on behalf of a diagnostic report, I give you a 25% discount on the diagnostic fee.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&#34;service-list-items&#34;&gt;I deliver cutting edge results to any hardware or software related problem with over twenty years of hardware experience while using the latest hardware diagnostic tools.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&#34;service-list-items&#34;&gt;A full diagnostic service can take twenty four to forty eight non-billable hours to complete. Sometimes a bit longer if I am backed up with work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&#34;service-list-items&#34;&gt;In some cases, comprehensive diagnostics on obscure problems can take longer, up to one or sometimes two non-billable weeks. Contact me about getting a loaner device in these situations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&#34;service-list-items&#34;&gt;Half-off all diagnostic work when repairs are authorized.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&#34;service-list-items&#34;&gt;This fee is per device.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;quote-panel-container&#34;&gt;
	&lt;div class=&#34;quote-panel-label&#34;&gt;
  	&lt;p&gt;Request Quote&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;quote-panel-item&#34;&gt;
  	&lt;div class=&#34;quote-panel-button&#34;&gt;
  		&lt;a href=&#34;http://scottrlarson.com/services/computer/assistance/phone&#34;&gt;Call&lt;/a&gt;
  	&lt;/div&gt;
  	&lt;div class=&#34;quote-panel-button&#34;&gt;
  		&lt;a href=&#34;http://scottrlarson.com/services/computer/assistance/quote&#34;&gt;On-line&lt;/a&gt;
  	&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Desktop</title>
      <link>http://scottrlarson.com/services/computer/repair/desktop/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2019 16:25:54 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scottrlarson.com/services/computer/repair/desktop/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;product-body&#34;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you are having a problem with your desktops hardware or software that requires a repair to fix the issue, I offer good prices, expert handling of your issue, with a quick turn around time usually between 24 and 48 hours depending on my availability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With over twenty years of hardware and software experience, I provide quick and comprehensive repair solutions to the most common and obscure computer problems. Don&#39;t let computer problems frustrate you and effect your productivity, &lt;a href=&#34;http://scottrlarson.com/services/computer/assistance/phone/&#34;&gt;Call&lt;/a&gt; me or &lt;a href=&#34;http://scottrlarson.com/#contact&#34;&gt;schedule an appointment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you are not sure what the problem is with your device please request a &lt;a href=&#34;http://scottrlarson.com/services/computer/repair/diagnostic/&#34;&gt;diagnostic&lt;/a&gt;. My diagnostic service allows for proper testing to occur so that complications prior to a repair are minimized.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you are requesting this repair service as part of a previous Diagnostic service, you will receive half-off of the diagnostic service fee as a credit upon completion of repairs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This Fee is per device. If you need more than one device repaired please order more than one Repair Service.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This fee does not include the costs of replacement parts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I guaranty my work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Replacement parts are guaranteed to be free from defects for up to one year minus the shipping cost for the return item and the replacement part.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;quote-panel-container&#34;&gt;
	&lt;div class=&#34;quote-panel-label&#34;&gt;
  	&lt;p&gt;Request Quote&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;quote-panel-item&#34;&gt;
  	&lt;div class=&#34;quote-panel-button&#34;&gt;
  		&lt;a href=&#34;http://scottrlarson.com/services/computer/assistance/phone&#34;&gt;Call&lt;/a&gt;
  	&lt;/div&gt;
  	&lt;div class=&#34;quote-panel-button&#34;&gt;
  		&lt;a href=&#34;http://scottrlarson.com/services/computer/assistance/quote&#34;&gt;On-line&lt;/a&gt;
  	&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upkeep (Hardware)</title>
      <link>http://scottrlarson.com/services/computer/repair/upkeep-hardware/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2019 15:48:51 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scottrlarson.com/services/computer/repair/upkeep-hardware/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Desktops and laptops can suffer from shutdowns, boot failures, errors, and system crashes related to blocked ventilation, aging of parts that protect the hardware from thermal damage, or mis-configured hardware. Having your device properly maintained on a regular basis improves the life of the hardware and can solve system failures that are happening as a result of heat or system mis-configurations by the device manufacturer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you ever heard of term planned obsolescence? Did you know that it&#39;s suspected that some device manufacturer&#39;s create design flaws that decrease the life of your device resulting in premature failures that result in abnormal replacement of your device? Here&#39;s how:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ventilation ports that allow the heat to dissipate from the hardware get clogged with dust, dirt, hair, and other particles. This causes the device to over-heat and shutdown, decreasing the life of the device.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Parts that distribute the flow of heat from hardware components have mountings that are sometimes made out of plastic. Plastic mounts that need to hold components in place or provide contact with heat dissipation parts break over time causing the part to fail to perform its function.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thermal paste that distributes the heat between the processor and the heat dissipation part can be made of low quality components and become brittle over a short time. Failure in the thermal paste performing its job causes overheating and results in permanent hardware failure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Setting the processor&#39;s clock at speed that the internal cooling systems have a hard time handling. Over time this excessive overheating causes the hardware to fail if the device is not serviced regularly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;If your device is getting to hot to the touch or you find its shutting down after a short period of use (between 3 minutes and a few hours), your device could need some proper hardware care or a design flaw analysis and resolution.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Excessive overheating for long periods of time can:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shorten the life of your device&amp;rsquo;s or laptop&amp;rsquo;s circuitry, causing instability that results in expensive hardware replacements.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your laptop battery&amp;rsquo;s life can be shortened significantly or your battery can even exploded due to heat caused by over charging.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How these problems can be resolved:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Diagnose the device to identify these problems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Perform a comprehensive cleaning of the ventilation ports involved in cooling the unit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apply high quality thermal solutions that keep the hardware free of overheating over a much longer period of time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Return the Processor settings to a normal state of operation to prevent heat damage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;quote-panel-container&#34;&gt;
	&lt;div class=&#34;quote-panel-label&#34;&gt;
  	&lt;p&gt;Request Quote&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;quote-panel-item&#34;&gt;
  	&lt;div class=&#34;quote-panel-button&#34;&gt;
  		&lt;a href=&#34;http://scottrlarson.com/services/computer/assistance/phone&#34;&gt;Call&lt;/a&gt;
  	&lt;/div&gt;
  	&lt;div class=&#34;quote-panel-button&#34;&gt;
  		&lt;a href=&#34;http://scottrlarson.com/services/computer/assistance/quote&#34;&gt;On-line&lt;/a&gt;
  	&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upkeep (General)</title>
      <link>http://scottrlarson.com/services/computer/repair/upkeep-general/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2019 15:48:04 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scottrlarson.com/services/computer/repair/upkeep-general/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Having recurring maintenance service in place prevents computer issues from turning into disasters. Regular computer maintenance is more than just an insurance policy. It keeps you informed and in the loop with where you are at any given moment to the status of your technology needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Analyze system for out-of-date hardware and offer cost effective recommendations for replacement&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;(Prevents performance problems with the operation of your computer).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Analyze System for Out-of-Date or Non-Functioning Drivers and Software&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;(Prevents problems with the operation of your device).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update System Drivers&lt;/strong&gt; (Prevents problems with the operation of your device).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Analyze System for System Errors that is or could potentially lead to system failures&lt;/strong&gt; (Prevents system and application failures).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Analyze current backup strategy and offer recommendations based on your current configuration&lt;/strong&gt; (Prevents data loss and downtime)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;quote-panel-container&#34;&gt;
	&lt;div class=&#34;quote-panel-label&#34;&gt;
  	&lt;p&gt;Request Quote&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;quote-panel-item&#34;&gt;
  	&lt;div class=&#34;quote-panel-button&#34;&gt;
  		&lt;a href=&#34;http://scottrlarson.com/services/computer/assistance/phone&#34;&gt;Call&lt;/a&gt;
  	&lt;/div&gt;
  	&lt;div class=&#34;quote-panel-button&#34;&gt;
  		&lt;a href=&#34;http://scottrlarson.com/services/computer/assistance/quote&#34;&gt;On-line&lt;/a&gt;
  	&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Malware Cleanup</title>
      <link>http://scottrlarson.com/services/computer/repair/cleanup/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2019 10:57:35 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scottrlarson.com/services/computer/repair/cleanup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If your device became infected by malware, I offer clean-up services that can resolve most infection related issues involving drive by attacks, trojans, adware, virus, rootkits, fake security solutions and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;quote-panel-container&#34;&gt;
	&lt;div class=&#34;quote-panel-label&#34;&gt;
  	&lt;p&gt;Request Quote&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;quote-panel-item&#34;&gt;
  	&lt;div class=&#34;quote-panel-button&#34;&gt;
  		&lt;a href=&#34;http://scottrlarson.com/services/computer/assistance/phone&#34;&gt;Call&lt;/a&gt;
  	&lt;/div&gt;
  	&lt;div class=&#34;quote-panel-button&#34;&gt;
  		&lt;a href=&#34;http://scottrlarson.com/services/computer/assistance/quote&#34;&gt;On-line&lt;/a&gt;
  	&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Online</title>
      <link>http://scottrlarson.com/services/computer/repair/online/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 16:18:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scottrlarson.com/services/computer/repair/online/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you have a question or problem with your device, and your Internet connection is still working, I can service your device over the Internet. I can speak with you over the phone while I am looking at the problem and give you a cost analysis.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Please inquire about protecting your data before I start the work. I am not responsible for any kind of data loss.  If you don&#39;t have one already, having a backup strategy is important before you request help so that none of your important data is lost in the event of a device failure or accident.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Types of issues that can be repaired as long as your device boots and is able to get on-line:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Software Application Crashing Issues&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Software Application Setup and Configuration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spyware Infections&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Non-functional devices&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Performance Issues&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Operating System Errors and Glitches&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Network File Sharing Problems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Video Display Problems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some forms of Data Loss&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Supported Devices&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Mac&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;PC&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Desktop&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Laptop&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;quote-panel-container&#34;&gt;
	&lt;div class=&#34;quote-panel-label&#34;&gt;
  	&lt;p&gt;Request Quote&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;quote-panel-item&#34;&gt;
  	&lt;div class=&#34;quote-panel-button&#34;&gt;
  		&lt;a href=&#34;http://scottrlarson.com/services/computer/assistance/phone&#34;&gt;Call&lt;/a&gt;
  	&lt;/div&gt;
  	&lt;div class=&#34;quote-panel-button&#34;&gt;
  		&lt;a href=&#34;http://scottrlarson.com/services/computer/assistance/quote&#34;&gt;On-line&lt;/a&gt;
  	&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
