<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>_Index on Scott Larson</title>
    <link>http://scottrlarson.com/home/</link>
    <description>Recent content in _Index on Scott Larson</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>2017 Scott Larson</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2018 14:01:15 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://scottrlarson.com/home/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://scottrlarson.com/home/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scottrlarson.com/home/about/</guid>
      <description>COVID Precautions As the new Omicron variant of the COVID virus spreads, I need to take precautions to protect everyone from infection. I provide remote service, curbside and at-your-location pick-up. Due to COVID, please call me, or make an online appointment before you arrive. Also please read and observe the following precautions to minimizing the spread of infection during this pandemic. Thank you.
 Professional Background   I am a computer and information technology professional.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selected Publications</title>
      <link>http://scottrlarson.com/home/publications_selected/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scottrlarson.com/home/publications_selected/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your Own Personal Trouble-shooter</title>
      <link>http://scottrlarson.com/home/work-ethics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Oct 2018 16:46:07 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scottrlarson.com/home/work-ethics/</guid>
      <description>Imagine that you have your own personal Computer Troubleshooter that has your back throughout the day, who has a wide range of expertise, and communicates technical subjects in a simple to understand manner? That also cares about your needs like his own, and keeps excellent records of all your service visits?
As your own personal troubleshooter, I excel in following up with in-progress projects and services, I stay abreast with the latest technologies that matter to you and I keep you in the loop on what you need to know to help you stay productive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recent Publications</title>
      <link>http://scottrlarson.com/home/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scottrlarson.com/home/publications/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Most Improved</title>
      <link>http://scottrlarson.com/home/publication-most-improved/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2019 13:40:53 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scottrlarson.com/home/publication-most-improved/</guid>
      <description>I authored a book on life and existence, if you want to find out more about my personal thoughts and feelings read on.
 &amp;ldquo;Most Improved&amp;rdquo; is a meditation on the process of personal transformation. I experienced a transformation from a &amp;ldquo;self-centered&amp;rdquo; worldly view on life, to a &amp;ldquo;universe-connected&amp;rdquo; consciousness, where all life has meaning. In August of 2017, I suffered a Cerebral Hemorrhage. While at work, I collapsed, was taken to the hospital, and diagnosed with high blood pressure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recent &amp; Upcoming Talks</title>
      <link>http://scottrlarson.com/home/talks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scottrlarson.com/home/talks/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recent Updates</title>
      <link>http://scottrlarson.com/home/updates/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scottrlarson.com/home/updates/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>http://scottrlarson.com/home/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scottrlarson.com/home/projects/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Custom Section</title>
      <link>http://scottrlarson.com/home/teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scottrlarson.com/home/teaching/</guid>
      <description>This is an example of using the custom widget to create your own homepage section.
To remove this section, either delete content/home/teaching.md or edit the frontmatter of the file to deactivate the widget by setting active = false.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tags</title>
      <link>http://scottrlarson.com/home/tags/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2017 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scottrlarson.com/home/tags/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Service Precautions</title>
      <link>http://scottrlarson.com/home/precautions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 11:28:31 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scottrlarson.com/home/precautions/</guid>
      <description>Please do not order any services if you, or, in the case of a at-location appointment, anyone in your household has shortness of breath, or has signs of any flu like symptoms.  When you arrive and before you enter the building please wear mask.  Walk-in customers who show up while I am with a customer, will be asked to contact me to make an appointment for a return visit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Repair Service Rates &amp; Turn-around Times</title>
      <link>http://scottrlarson.com/home/service-repair-rates-turnaround/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 10:00:49 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scottrlarson.com/home/service-repair-rates-turnaround/</guid>
      <description>Priority Within 1-2 Days  $165-$473  Skip the line. Priority response to calls, texts, emails. Saturday service Free your location priority pickup and drop off service (If needed or requested). High quality repair service with over 20 years of experience. Full diagnostic service &amp; reports (If needed)  Expert advise and recommendations on future issues and purchases. Excellent service record/history keeping. Access to articles and publications that will simplify your technology life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Consultation Service Rates</title>
      <link>http://scottrlarson.com/home/service-consultation-rates/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 10:43:52 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scottrlarson.com/home/service-consultation-rates/</guid>
      <description>Consultations can happen in my office, or at your location. Rates are based on location and distance and starts at $125 an hour with a one hour minimum. Depending on my service load, at office/home appointments usually carry a three hour to one day service visit priority, but when my service load is high, I reserve the right to push at-location appointments service requests to a lower priority, between one to three days, or in rare cases, up to a week.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>http://scottrlarson.com/home/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scottrlarson.com/home/contact/</guid>
      <description>First Name   Last Name   Best Contact Number   Your Email   Details   Secondary Contact      Send Request    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hours</title>
      <link>http://scottrlarson.com/home/hours/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scottrlarson.com/home/hours/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>