<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Meditation on Scott Larson</title>
    <link>http://scottrlarson.com/tags/meditation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Meditation on Scott Larson</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>2017 Scott Larson</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2019 13:40:53 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/meditation/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Most Improved</title>
      <link>http://scottrlarson.com/books/book-most-improved/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2019 13:40:53 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scottrlarson.com/books/book-most-improved/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A story of transformation from selfishness to selflessness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Most Improved&amp;rdquo; is a meditation on the process of personal transformation. I experienced a transformation from a &amp;ldquo;self-centered&amp;rdquo; worldly view on life, to a &amp;ldquo;universe-connected&amp;rdquo; consciousness, where all life has meaning. In August of 2017, I suffered a Cerebral Hemorrhage. While at work, I collapsed, was taken to the hospital, and diagnosed with high blood pressure. My recovery was a miracle, I suffer only minor damage to my body&amp;rsquo;s sensory systems, that improved over time. While recovering in the ICU, and realizing that I was not going to die, I got in touch with a deep feeling of apathy, and sadness about my life.  I realized that previously, I was covering up these feelings with day-to-day distractions. I decided that if I was going to survive, I was going to live differently this time. This determination brought me to place where I developed an understanding on how to really live. I learned from many people including: Mark Passio, James Allen, and David K. Reynolds. I combine Hermetic principles with the Constructive Living practices of David K. Reynolds, and I filter all of that though the ethical teachings of James Allen. In this book I expose how aligning oneself to Cosmic Law brings true happiness. If you want to experience a fellow &amp;ldquo;life-traveler&amp;rsquo;s&amp;rdquo; view on overcoming depression, or just want to learn about the state of the world from a modern, self-learned philosopher, then this book is for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Purchase the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Most-Improved-transformation-selfishness-selflessness-ebook/dp/B07N5K9FCH/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;kindle&lt;/a&gt; version on Amazon Kindle Direct Publishing.&lt;br /&gt;
Purchase the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/dp/1795274042&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;paperback&lt;/a&gt; version on Amazon Books.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
