<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Terms of Service on Scott Larson</title>
    <link>http://scottrlarson.com/terms/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Terms of Service on Scott Larson</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>2017 Scott Larson</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2018 14:11:07 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://scottrlarson.com/terms/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Service Authorization</title>
      <link>http://scottrlarson.com/terms/service-authorization/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Nov 2021 15:55:52 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scottrlarson.com/terms/service-authorization/</guid>
      <description>Terms of Service &amp;amp; Limited Liability You authorize my service when you bring in your device, request service via other means, for instance, but not limited to, an E-mail or Phone request. I will have you approve the service by an Authorization or Order Form. You can approve this authorization or order by signature, or voice or text your approval in a phone conversation or an electronic/letter communication. When you authorize this service I have a responsibility to provided to you a reliable and good experience/outcome.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who can request service</title>
      <link>http://scottrlarson.com/terms/who/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jun 2018 09:58:06 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scottrlarson.com/terms/who/</guid>
      <description>I provide technical service solely to individuals. If you own a business or you work for a business all service related dealings will be handled by you and I. If you want someone else to engage with me on a service in question on your behalf, please provide your consent in writing to allow that someone to speak for you and act on your behalf.
When you request a service from me, recurring or otherwise, it is by contract.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Response Times</title>
      <link>http://scottrlarson.com/terms/response/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jun 2018 09:58:26 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scottrlarson.com/terms/response/</guid>
      <description>Unless my work schedule is nearing the end of the day, I will respond to communications within three hours, or less. There are a few exceptions to this time frame: If I am on a emergency appointment where I cannot get away, I am on vacation, I am out sick, or it is during off hours. If I am occupied with any of these situations, I will respond to any and all communications on the next business day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Service Priority</title>
      <link>http://scottrlarson.com/terms/priority/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2018 09:17:20 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scottrlarson.com/terms/priority/</guid>
      <description>I operate on a first come, first serve basis. Unless you want a priory service. If you need a faster turn-around, see my priority rates.
During my regular service schedule, I always prioritize customers that have already paid for service, over those that have an outstanding payment that is due.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Payments</title>
      <link>http://scottrlarson.com/terms/payments/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2019 14:17:05 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scottrlarson.com/terms/payments/</guid>
      <description>All payments can be made via check or cash. If you prefer to pay by credit card, you can paypal me, or venmo me at @scottRlarson. On Venmo, my handle is connected to the business part of their service. So if you do not see my listing, switch to the business tab.
In-shop Servicing Payments are due upon pick-up of your device.
At-location I require payment before I leave the location where I provide you service unless special arrangements are made for recurring service in advance (regardless of the outcome).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Responsible Communication</title>
      <link>http://scottrlarson.com/terms/communication/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jun 2018 09:58:47 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scottrlarson.com/terms/communication/</guid>
      <description>Its very important to me that I provide the best possible service and that means that after I completed my service on your device, I want to return your device to you in a timely manner. I rely on you to provide me with timely responses to my requests, especially if you require a quick turn-around on the service of your device.
In certain cases, failure to follow up on my request for communication in a timely manner may increase the chance of a delay with other customer&amp;rsquo;s services.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Limited Liability</title>
      <link>http://scottrlarson.com/terms/liability/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2018 15:53:44 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scottrlarson.com/terms/liability/</guid>
      <description>Protecting Your Data I make every effort to protect your data, but I am not responsible nor liable for preserving your data, or knowing what kind of data existed before the servicing of any device. I perform backups of your device a before a start a service, but my backups are for internal use and done for safety reasons only. If something goes wrong with a servicing, I can use this backup to restore the computer to its original configuration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Appointment Scheduling</title>
      <link>http://scottrlarson.com/terms/appointments/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jun 2018 10:00:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scottrlarson.com/terms/appointments/</guid>
      <description>If you require an at-location or in-shop consultation contact me to make an appointment. Please note that making appointments with me require both of us to be prompt and communicative about delays/cancellations ahead of time by at least 2hrs. If I fail to show up for our appointment I will wave the first hour of the consultation. If I am late for an appointment over 10mins I will take %25 off your fee.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your Time Frame Expectations</title>
      <link>http://scottrlarson.com/terms/time/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jun 2018 10:02:21 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scottrlarson.com/terms/time/</guid>
      <description>During the evaluation or in-take period, I will do my best to communicate to you the length of time a service might require. With certain technical problems, the length of time to service your device can range from a couple hours, days, or even weeks depending on the issue, and the time may change depending on what crops up during the servicing. If you cannot be without your device for the length of time specified above, purchase a backup device, or ask me about acquiring a temporary replacement loaner device.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Right to Self-Regulation</title>
      <link>http://scottrlarson.com/terms/self-regulation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jun 2018 10:01:30 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scottrlarson.com/terms/self-regulation/</guid>
      <description>All my rights as a service providing individual are reserved.
When I provide you a service, or if an arrangement that benefits both parties is agreed upon, or in the works, I reserve the right not to subject myself to background checks, licenses to do business, be employed by another, or any process that subjects me to any authority other than my own.
Please note that this right is not a claim of lawlessness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your Privacy</title>
      <link>http://scottrlarson.com/terms/privacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scottrlarson.com/terms/privacy/</guid>
      <description>Communication Privacy Statement During the servicing of your device, by your request, I may have to access certain areas of your file system, or online accounts, that might contain private information. I will not knowingly take any action that involves breaching the privacy to your digital information in any way. I take every effort within my ability to secure any private/personal communications/data from any locations that I service devices at.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Responsibilities</title>
      <link>http://scottrlarson.com/terms/responsibility/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 08:29:47 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scottrlarson.com/terms/responsibility/</guid>
      <description>As a professional computer technician, I&amp;rsquo;m responsible for addressing operational related issues with technology at the time of servicing.
Preexisting unrelated/related software or hardware problems can be revealed at any time during the servicing. Occasionally these problems can be missed during a servicing. These issues can cause pervasive and reoccurring issues that may require follow-up and secondary servicing/intervention to resolve.
When these rare situations arise, If I spot the issue during my servicing I will reach out to you to let you know of a problem, when this happens, I may need to perform a diagnostic to resolve the issue, I will bill you for my diagnostic time under these circumstances, if you have any questions about these follow up fees, please contact me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Service Guarantee</title>
      <link>http://scottrlarson.com/terms/service-guarantee/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 08:52:52 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scottrlarson.com/terms/service-guarantee/</guid>
      <description>All my services are guaranteed to be free of mistakes in servicemanship. Any device purchased from me that has parts containing a replacement guarantee from the manufacturer, also carries my 1 year labor replacement warranty from the day of purchase.  Software support is usually outside of the scope of my Service Guarantee If you request software or a service to be setup, maintained, or repaired on your device/s, and you require support during or after my servicing, I may be required to interact with the software or service provider to resolve the issue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Device Diagnostic, Repairs &amp; Remote Management</title>
      <link>http://scottrlarson.com/terms/device-repairs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2020 08:52:29 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scottrlarson.com/terms/device-repairs/</guid>
      <description>Diagnostics and Analysis Services Diagnostic fees cover my time in troubleshooting an issue, and for me to provide you with a expert report on what I think the problem is based on my observations, or for me to provide you with a recommendation in the event the device unable to be repaired due to time or cost.
Providing Service Prerequisites When you bring your device in for servicing, after a repair, or when you agree to allow me to remotely manage your device&amp;rsquo;s security, backup or upkeep, I may install certain applications/shortcuts on your desktop that help provide ongoing services or to maintain a business relationship.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Transfer Services</title>
      <link>http://scottrlarson.com/terms/transfers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 11:31:16 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scottrlarson.com/terms/transfers/</guid>
      <description>Please be aware that migrating to and from different technologies can result in problems with 3rd party hardware or software. I am your facilitator in that process, I am not representative for these third party technologies that are out of my control. If I encounter an issue with any 3rd party technology (Hardware or Software that was not setup by me), I may need to troubleshoot/diagnose the issue, handled under my diagnostic fees, before I can continue the work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Device Setup</title>
      <link>http://scottrlarson.com/terms/new-device-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2018 14:36:04 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scottrlarson.com/terms/new-device-setup/</guid>
      <description>When you purchase a device from me, bring a new device in for setup or a tune-up, I will remove or replace features that I deem best for my customers. These fine tuning operations are done to improve customer experience.
This might include removing, or replacing (also by your request): security software, preloaded apps that are not part of the required core functionality of the system, or hardware that is causing performance bottlenecks.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>