<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Guides on Scott Larson</title>
    <link>http://scottrlarson.com/guides/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Guides on Scott Larson</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>2017 Scott Larson</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2018 09:33:32 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://scottrlarson.com/guides/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Check PC Hardware Temperatures</title>
      <link>http://scottrlarson.com/guides/guide-checking-hardware-temperatures/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 16:02:41 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scottrlarson.com/guides/guide-checking-hardware-temperatures/</guid>
      <description>You alone are responsible and liable for any action you take as a result of reading this information.
Occasionally, hardware problems like bluescreens and system or video errors can be related to too high of hardware temperatures. Problems related to hardware temperatures usually appear intermittent, but they usually start to happen after the computer has been running for awhile, or when a resource intensive application has been running for awhile.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Managing Macrium Reflect Backups For Beginners</title>
      <link>http://scottrlarson.com/guides/guide-macrium-reflect-basic-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2020 14:57:52 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scottrlarson.com/guides/guide-macrium-reflect-basic-management/</guid>
      <description>Macrium Software was founded in 2006 when CEO and Founder Nick Sills experienced a personal data disaster and in the process discovered existing backup tools were not as good as he expected. Wanting a software solution that was practical and easy to use, Nick and his team developed Macrium Reflect to create a safe and secure disk image with ultra-fast recovery times.
This is a guide to help beginners perform some operations of managing their own backups.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Removing Duplicate Photos from your PC.</title>
      <link>http://scottrlarson.com/guides/technology/guide-removing-duplicate-photos-dupeguru/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2018 09:32:03 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scottrlarson.com/guides/technology/guide-removing-duplicate-photos-dupeguru/</guid>
      <description>This guide shows you how to scan and remove duplicate photos using the PC application &amp;ldquo;dupeGuru&amp;rdquo;.
Launch DupeGuru from the desktop icon. Select the application mode for the appropriate files you are going to be scanning for: Standard, Music, or Pictures.
Since this guide is going to be for Pictures choose that mode. Tap on the plus icon to choose the folders to scan for duplicates. On the left column, choose &amp;ldquo;This PC&amp;rdquo; and then select your &amp;ldquo;Pictures&amp;rdquo; folder then click &amp;ldquo;Select Folder&amp;rdquo; at the bottom right.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>