<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Education on Scott Larson</title>
    <link>http://scottrlarson.com/education/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Education on Scott Larson</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>2017 Scott Larson</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 13:55:24 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/education/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Apprenticeship Opportunity</title>
      <link>http://scottrlarson.com/education/apprentice-opportunity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 13:55:05 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scottrlarson.com/education/apprentice-opportunity/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I am interested in training an apprentice in my field. If you, or someone you know, are/is interested in an in-depth understanding of how hardware and software computer technology works to be able to troubleshoot your own computer problems, or build your own computer, this apprenticeship opportunity is for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a very special arrangement for a student, or an adult that is willing to learn new ideas in how to provide a successful Computer Repair or Information Technology service. This is a voluntary time giving initiative on my part which (if interested) could lead to a paid working relationship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have over 25 years experience with computer technology, but I also have many other interests that impacts how I operate my service to the community. I have worked with many computing platforms. I started with the Commodore brand in the eighties and then moved on to the PC platform in the nineties. In between that I was also working with Apple hardware and the Unix environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My main interests are in gaming technology. I&amp;rsquo;m a old school gamer at heart and am currently working toward learning how to develop my own games. I prefer open source software, but in many cases I also work with closed source software when an open source alternative isn&amp;rsquo;t available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventual I would like to apprentice two individuals. One who is interested in repairing/upgrading laptops and another repairing upgrading desktops.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;main-requirements&#34;&gt;Main Requirements&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Must be 18 years of age or older&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be available 2-3 days per week (Depending on my work load)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be available 2-4 hours per day (Depending on my work load)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Live in Santa Rosa, California or the surrounding area within 20 miles.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have reliable transportation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;laptop-technician-requirements&#34;&gt;Laptop Technician Requirements&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have 20/20 or better eyesight or have equivalent with prescriptions eyewear.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have good dexterity in handling very small electronic parts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Willing to learn how to handle delicate parts in a methodical way.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Willingness to learn how to follow a standard procedure during servicing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;desktop-technician-requirements&#34;&gt;Desktop Technician Requirements&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have 20/20 or better eyesight or have equivalent with prescriptions eyewear.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have good dexterity in handling electronic parts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Willingness to learn how to follow a standard procedure during servicing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;commitment-requirements&#34;&gt;Commitment Requirements&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Willingness to learn, even when the tasks does not seem related to the project at hand.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Willingness to be open to new ideas and concepts outside of your current belief system that leads to professionalism in the field of computer technology.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Willingness to be patient with the some times slow process of getting to the next task in a project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;skills-you-will-learn&#34;&gt;Skills You Will Learn&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Computer Hardware Assembly/Building&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hardware Troubleshooting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Laptop Disassembly/Reassembly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Customer, Service, Inventory Tracking (Important for computer repair business, but also helps personal time investment in tracking progress of any project)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Willingness to develop a strong work ethic (Helps apprentice with life in general in working relationships with others)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are interested please &lt;a href=&#34;http://scottrlarson.com/#contact&#34;&gt;contact me&lt;/a&gt;, I will get back to you at my earliest opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
