<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Newsletters on Scott Larson</title>
    <link>http://scottrlarson.com/newsletters/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Newsletters on Scott Larson</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>2017 Scott Larson</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Mar 2018 19:02:10 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://scottrlarson.com/newsletters/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Scooter&#39;s Fall Newsletter: Whats your backup plan?, Solid State Storage Technology, and Scott&#39;s New Office</title>
      <link>http://scottrlarson.com/newsletters/2018-oct/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2018 15:08:19 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scottrlarson.com/newsletters/2018-oct/</guid>
      <description>Hi, this is Scott Larson you signed up for my quarterly Scooter newsletter from a previous engagement. I also had a class at my office location on learning the basics of the Windows 10 desktop in June of 2018. If you missed it you can check out the slides on my website.
In these newsletters I write about new technologies I discover and use in the field. I also deliver solutions based on these discoveries to my customers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scooters June 2018 Newsletter: Finger Print Sign-In, Duplicate Files, and Tracking Customer History</title>
      <link>http://scottrlarson.com/newsletters/2018-june/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 17:12:31 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scottrlarson.com/newsletters/2018-june/</guid>
      <description>Hi, this is Scott Larson you signed up for my quarterly Scooter newsletter from a previous engagement. I had a class on learning the basics of the Windows 10 desktop. If you missed it you can check out the slides on my website.
In these newsletters I write about new technologies I discover and use in the field. I also deliver solutions based on these discoveries to my customers. You benefit from these discoveries as I write about how they improve my customer’s lives.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>