<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>_Index on Scott Larson</title>
    <link>http://scottrlarson.com/experience/</link>
    <description>Recent content in _Index on Scott Larson</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>2017 Scott Larson</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 11:56:59 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/experience/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Information Services Experience</title>
      <link>http://scottrlarson.com/experience/information-services/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 11:57:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scottrlarson.com/experience/information-services/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;it-setup-troubleshooting-and-repair&#34;&gt;IT Setup, Troubleshooting and Repair&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From 2000 - 2006 I worked for a company called Sonic.com in Novato. Back then Sonic.com was a Multimedia authoring software company that made software products for audio and video professionals. I came in as their systems administrator. At that time I already had lots of experience with the inner workings with computers, but that was the first time I started to learn about handling technology on a service level. Where I was a liaison between the company and vendors of various Internet services like mail and websites. But I also maintained the companies internal servers and services. I gained a lot of experience with how mail servers and website servers communicate on the back end to the point where I could trouble-shoot and resolve most communication problems related to why websites were not display content correctly, or why email was not being delivered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My business revolves around maintaining and managing desktops, websites, and mail related services for companies, but I mostly handle special cases where the IT staff neither has the time or the knowhow to handle these issues.  Sometimes a vendor, a general IT person or a web developer can handle it, sometimes it requires someone with expertise in specific areas of technology. I have extensive experience with communication protocols and computer hardware/software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An example of this was a customer of mine called me and explained that their web designer was having trouble with getting their website contact form to talk to their hosting provider&amp;rsquo;s mail server. The hosting provider in this case was Godaddy. Godaddy doesn&amp;rsquo;t actually support this issue because from their point of view the customers mail service is working and the contact form script in question was having the problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This ended up being a problem with a secondary mail provider that Godaddy was was using to serve the customer email. The security measures (to prevent spam) was preventing the website contact form from talking to email server. I had to configure the website contact form to handle these new security measures. But sometimes I switch a customer to a less strict mail solution and migrate their mail if they don&amp;rsquo;t need that kind of security so that the form can talk to the mail server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other times, web developers are handed a pre-existing website that is old and have to figure out why some legacy code isn&amp;rsquo;t working the way it&amp;rsquo;s expected after they give the site a face lift. One time I came in and actually had to use a network analysis tool to see what kind of response the legacy code was sending to the website visitor so I could isolate the problem code. The result was that after I found where the site was failing to serve content in the code itself, I gave the customer (Web Developers) the location of the legacy code. It was a image caching solution that was not working with the new development of the site. Once they removed that code the page with the problem started working again.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
