<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>PC Gaming on Scott Larson</title>
    <link>http://scottrlarson.com/categories/pc-gaming/</link>
    <description>Recent content in PC Gaming on Scott Larson</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>2017 Scott Larson</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2022 11:57:44 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/categories/pc-gaming/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Gamer&#39;s Friday - Mordheim - City of the Damned</title>
      <link>http://scottrlarson.com/updates/update-mordheim-city-of-the-damned/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2022 11:57:44 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scottrlarson.com/updates/update-mordheim-city-of-the-damned/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;In 2018 my Mordheim play-through ended abruptly. A quarter of the way in, I suffered a brain hemorrhage. My miraculous recovery changed my life for the better and you can read about my experience in my &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.scottrlarson.com/books/book-most-improved/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;book&lt;/a&gt;, but now I am finally getting back into gaming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I find 1st/3rd person perspective strategy games interesting. Maybe because I prefer unconventional gameplay. This one is Turn-based, which is an interesting take on a game that has fighting elements in various locations of Mordheim. Once a great imperial city, now overrun with corruption of the magical and divine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://scottrlarson.com/img/gamers-friday/mordheim-wyrestone-collection.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Wyrestone Campfire&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The game puts you as a commander of a Warband bent on gathering precious Wyrestone to keep your Barron happy. There are story missions weaved through the game, appearing to loosely follow the Book &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Gotrek-Felix-Damned-David-Guymer/dp/1849705291&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;City of the Damned&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo;, based on the Warhammer Universe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your Warband gains experience fighting battles and collecting Wyrestone on the streets of Mordheim. Encounters require patience and careful planning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interesting side note: See the game &lt;a href=&#34;https://store.steampowered.com/app/624970/Battlezone_Combat_Commander/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Battlezone II&lt;/a&gt; for the king of the real-time strategy genre.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Missions are a grind though and made terribly slow when you have to manually issue commands to each Warrior every round, even when they are not engaged in any actions, some automation would have been nice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://scottrlarson.com/img/gamers-friday/mordheim-consoles-03.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Tank&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don&amp;rsquo;t mind your Warband&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Hired Swords&amp;rdquo; falling in battle, or becoming maimed, affecting combat effectiveness, then this game is for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The game is well done in my view even for its shortcomings. With so many AAA titles trying to be everything to everyone, any game that puts survival front a center deserves my respect.  I wholeheartedly recommend trying this &lt;a href=&#34;https://store.steampowered.com/app/276810/Mordheim_City_of_the_Damned/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;game&lt;/a&gt; out. Let me know what you think of it on &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/scottrlarson/status/1560708175799541760&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-custom-gaming-service-plug&#34;&gt;My Custom Gaming Service Plug&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am a gamer a heart, I started gaming when I was 12.  I want other gamers to know that I take a special interest in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.scottrlarson.com/services/computer/multimedia-gaming/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;customizing gaming builds and hardware upgrades&lt;/a&gt; for hardcore and average gamers. If you or someone you know is interested in purchasing a new gaming machine, instead of going the pre-built route, get the proper built quality with support from a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.scottrlarson.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;experienced hardware professional&lt;/a&gt;. Don&amp;rsquo;t take the risk of getting a built that suffers from quality assurance mishaps or inexperienced build designing by companies that don&amp;rsquo;t have your particular best interests at heart.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
