<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Guides on Scott Larson</title>
    <link>http://scottrlarson.com/categories/guides/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Guides on Scott Larson</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>2017 Scott Larson</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2020 09:00:53 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://scottrlarson.com/categories/guides/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How to check Battery level via Command line</title>
      <link>http://scottrlarson.com/updates/update-battery-life-via-cmd-line/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2020 09:00:53 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scottrlarson.com/updates/update-battery-life-via-cmd-line/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes, the battery indicator in Windows 10 stops working, fails to respond, or disappears. In this case you might need to check your battery life, until that problem gets fixed.
Check Battery level using command line Open Windows Command Prompt and execute the following command:
WMIC PATH Win32_Battery Get EstimatedChargeRemaining  The output for that command would look something like this:
 EstimatedCharge
Remaining
 You can see the estimated battery charge remaining.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scooters&#39; Laptop Buyers Guide</title>
      <link>http://scottrlarson.com/publications/publication-laptop-buyers-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 10:55:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scottrlarson.com/publications/publication-laptop-buyers-guide/</guid>
      <description>During my repairs, I receive quite a few PC laptops that are designed and constructed on the cheap. I speak to each of my customers about their purchasing choice, and if they can remember, it usually boils down to a purchase by marketing gimmick. While researching this publication, I looked up this phrase and the search results seem to think that performing a marketing gimmick is a great idea. Where I come from, marketing gimmicks are used to obfuscate the true colors of a product.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Restoring your digital life from backup after a disaster</title>
      <link>http://scottrlarson.com/publications/publication-restoring-life-backup-disaster/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2019 14:44:47 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scottrlarson.com/publications/publication-restoring-life-backup-disaster/</guid>
      <description>Learn why solely backing up your data isn&amp;rsquo;t always enough to recover from a disaster.
In this publication, you will learn about:
 What is disaster recovery backup, and why should I care? How a little planning can drive a successful disaster recovery Why waiting for a disaster to happen before you plan is a bad idea Understanding technology terms  Knowing the difference between backup and disaster recovery, understanding key technology terms, and evaluating software along with storage options can help you develop an effective plan for avoiding the consequences of data loss and downtime after a catastrophe strikes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>